

Obaid Ashfaq

Ruby on Rails Developer

in obaidashfa20

PROFILE

Ruby developer, enthusiastic about writing clean, efficient, and accessible code in a functional framework. Being curious to know, the hindrances felt like steps to move on further. Always confident in solving new problems and facing challenges. Assuring Quality and following best code practices are the prime focus. Hands-on experience with Ruby, Rails, EC2, Heroku, and Sinatra. Experience with package managers and dependencies i.e. rvm yarn, pip, and other command-line tools.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tkxel, Software Engineer

03/2022 - present | Lahore

Been building a test suite for a complete monolithic application in Ruby on Rails. Creating reports in simplecov using RSpec as the testing framework.

Evoke Team, Ruby on Rails Developer

12/2021 - 02/2022 | Lahore

Key responsibilities include resolving bugs and developing new features. Serving probation period IN learning and exploring ongoing projects

ExDevs, Full Stack Developer

09/2020 - 11/2021 | Lahore

Deployed test-driven development using Rspec and Sidekiq [Background workers]. Integrated tryotter in rails application (Adapter: Structural design pattern)

Ruby Developer, AntonX

11/2019 - 08/2020 | Peshawar

Developed web services with ruby and python; solutions to most of the hectic manual things. The application used Heroku as a cloud platform.

EDUCATION

BS Computer Systems Engineering,

University of Engineering and Technology ☑ 08/2019 | Peshawar, Pakistan

PROJECTS

Ministerial Development 2

03/2022 - 11/2022

Oversaw the development of documentation. Worked closely with clients and cross-functional departments to communicate project statuses and proposals. Analyzed data to effectively coordinate the installation of new systems or the modification of existing systems. Worked with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, AWS, and Elastic BeanStalk Using git as a version control system. Shipped features and resolved bugs following the best code practices. Managed the deployments on AWS instance using Elasticbeanstalk.

Automation Application

09/2021 - 11/2021

The application was written in Sinatra, a light framework of ruby that helps to automate tasks e.g if a branch or pull request is created update Jira and Trello accordingly tasks without user interaction, fetching the branch names from PR commits [following a particular convention] Notify via slack if the review app is created or deployed to staging using Heroku as a cloud platform. Rake tasks that check the time passed to the last commit to a particular PR and accomplished the automation of the whole workflow successfully, enabling the customer to operate with a much more efficient database.

TOOLS

Sinatra is a DSL for quickly creating web applications

Git|eb|heroku-cli|rvm

a distributed version control system

RSpec|Capybara|FactoryBot|SimpleCOV •

Testing along with coverage, mocking and stubbing

Active Admin|Devise|Pundit|VCR

mostly used gems in rails development

